The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: One more exacting lecture on hashing.
教授：关于哈希的另一门严谨的演讲。
And a couple reminders.
还有一些提醒。
I don't want to start out saying unpopular things,
我不想开始说不受欢迎的话，
but we do have a quiz coming up next week on Tuesday.
但是下周二我们确实有一个测验。
There will not be a lecture next Tuesday,
下周二将不会有演讲，
but there will be a quiz.
但是会有一个测验。
7:30 to 9:30 Tuesday evening.
周二晚上7:30至9:30。
I will send announcement.
我将发送公告。
There's going to be a couple rooms.
将有几个房间。
Some of you will be in this room.
你们当中有些人会在这个房间里。
Some of you will have to go to a different room,
你们中有些人必须去另一个房间，
since this room really can't hold
因为这个房间真的不能容纳
180 students taking a quiz.
180名学生参加测验。
All right?
好吧？
So hashing.
所以哈希。
I'm pretty excited about this lecture,
我对这次演讲感到非常兴奋，
because I think as I was talking with Victor just
因为我认为当我与Victor交谈时
before this, if there's one thing you want to remember
在此之前，如果您想记住一件事
about hashing and you want to go implement a hash table,
关于哈希，您想去实现哈希表，
it's open addressing.
它是开放地址。
It's the simplest way that you can possibly
这是最简单的方法
implement a hash table.
实现哈希表。
You can implement a hash table using an array.
您可以使用数组实现哈希表。
We've obviously talked about link lists
我们显然已经在谈论链接列表
and chaining to implement hash tables in previous lectures,
和链接以实现以前的讲座中的哈希表，
but we're going to actually get rid of pointers and link lists,
但实际上我们将摆脱指针和链接列表，
and implement a hash table using a single array data structure,
并使用单个数组数据结构实现哈希表，
and that's the notion of open addressing.
这就是开放寻址的概念。
Now in order to get open addressing to work,
现在，为了获得公开的地址，
there's no free lunch, right?
没有免费的午餐吧？
So you have a simple implementation.
因此，您有一个简单的实现。
It turns out that in order to make open addressing efficient,
事实证明，为了提高公开寻址的效率，
you have to be a little more careful than if you're
您必须比自己更小心一点
using the hash tables with chaining.
将哈希表与链接一起使用。
And we're going to have to make an assumption
我们将不得不做一个假设
about uniform hashing.
关于统一哈希。
I'll say a little bit more about that.
我会说更多。
But it's a different assumption from simple uniform hashing
但这是与简单的统一哈希不同的假设
that Eric talked about.
埃里克谈到的。
And we'll state this uniform hashing assumption.
我们将陈述这种统一的哈希假设。
And we look at what the performance is of open
我们看一下开放的表现
addressing under this assumption.
在这种假设下解决。
And this is assumption is going to give us
这是假设将给我们
a sense of what good hash functions are
了解什么是好的哈希函数
for open addressing applications or for open addressing
用于开放式寻址应用程序或用于开放式寻址
hash tables.
哈希表。
And finally we'll talk about cryptographic hashing.
最后，我们将讨论密码哈希。
This is not really 6006 material,
这不是真正的6006材料，
but it's kind of cool material.
但这是一种很酷的材料。
It has a lot of applications in computer security
它在计算机安全方面有很多应用
and cryptography.
和密码学。
And so as we'll describe the notion of a cryptographic hash,
因此，当我们描述密码哈希的概念时，
and we'll talk about a couple of real simple and pervasive
我们将讨论几个真正简单而普遍的方法
applications like password storage
密码存储等应用
and file corruption detectors that you can implement
和可以实现的文件损坏检测器
using cryptographic hash functions, which
使用加密散列函数
are quite different from the regular hash functions
与常规哈希函数有很大不同
that we're using in hash tables.
我们在哈希表中使用的
Be it chaining hash tables or open addressing hash tables.
是链接哈希表还是打开寻址哈希表。
All right?
好吧？
So let's get started and talk about open addressing.
因此，让我们开始讨论开放式寻址。
This is another approach to dealing with collisions.
这是处理冲突的另一种方法。
If you didn't have collisions, obviously an array
如果没有碰撞，显然是一个数组
would work, right?
会起作用，对吧？
If you could somehow guarantee that there were no collisions.
如果您能以某种方式保证没有碰撞。
When you have collisions, you have
发生碰撞时
to worry about the chaining and ensuring
担心链接和确保
that you can still find the keys even though you
即使您仍然可以找到钥匙
had two keys that collided into the same slot.
有两个撞到同一个插槽的钥匙。
And we don't want to use chaining.
而且我们不想使用链接。
The simplest data structure that we can possibly use are arrays.
我们可能使用的最简单的数据结构是数组。
Back when I was a grad student, I went through and got a PhD
当我还是研究生时，我通过了博士学位
writing programs in C, never using any other structure
用C编写程序，从不使用任何其他结构
than arrays, because I didn't like pointers.
比数组，因为我不喜欢指针。
And so open addressing is a way that you
因此，开放式寻址是您
can implement hash tables doing exactly this.
可以实现哈希表正是这样做的。
And in particular, what we're going to do
特别是我们要做的是
is assume an array structure with items.
假定包含项的数组结构。
And we're going to assume that this one item-- at most
我们将假设这一项目-最多
one item per slot.
每个插槽一个物品。
So m has to be greater than or equal to n, right?
所以m必须大于或等于n，对吗？
So this is important because we don't have link lists.
所以这很重要，因为我们没有链接列表。
We can't arbitrarily increase the storage
我们不能随意增加存储量
of a slot using a chain, and have
使用链条的插槽，并具有
n, which is the number of elements,
n，即元素数，
be greater than m, right?
大于m，对不对？
Which you could in the link list table with chaining.
您可以在链接列表表中进行链接。
But here you only have these area locations,
但是这里您只有这些区域位置，
these indices that you can put items into.
这些可以放入项目的索引。
So it's pretty much guaranteed that if you want a working open
因此，几乎可以保证，如果您想工作的话
addressing hash table that m, which is the number of slots
寻址哈希表m，即槽数
in the table, should be greater than or equal to the number
在表格中，应大于或等于数字
of elements, all right?
元素，好吗？
That's important.
那很重要
Now how does this work.
现在这是如何工作的。
Well, we're going to have this notion of probing.
好吧，我们将拥有这种探测概念。
And the notion of probing is that we're
探测的概念是我们
going to try to see if we can insert something
尝试看看我们是否可以插入一些东西
into this hash table, and if you fail
进入这个哈希表，如果失败
we're actually going to recompute
我们实际上将要重新计算
a slightly different hash for the key
密钥的哈希值略有不同
that we're trying to insert, the key value
我们试图插入的键值
pair that we're trying to insert.
我们试图插入的一对。
All right?
好吧？
So this is an iterative process, and we're
这是一个反复的过程，
going to continually probe until we find an empty slot
将不断进行探测，直到找到一个空插槽
into which we can insert this key value pair.
我们可以在其中插入该键值对。
The key should index into it.
密钥应该索引到其中。
So you do have different hashes that
所以你有不同的哈希值
are going to be computed based on this probing
将基于此探测进行计算
notion for a given key.
给定密钥的概念。
All right?
好吧？
And so what we need now is a hash function
因此，我们现在需要的是哈希函数
that's different from the standard hash functions
与标准哈希函数不同
that we've talked about so far, which specifies
到目前为止我们已经讨论过的
the order of slots to probe, which is basically
要探测的插槽的顺序，基本上是
to try for a key.
尝试一把钥匙。
And this is going to be true for insert, search, and delete,
这对于插入，搜索和删除都是正确的，
which are three basic operations.
这是三个基本操作。
And they're a little bit different, all right?
它们有些不同，好吗？
Just like they were different for the chaining hash table,
就像它们在链接哈希表方面有所不同一样，
they're different here, but they're kind of more different
它们在这里是不同的，但是它们却有所不同
here.
这里。
And you'll see what I mean when we go through this.
当我们经历这个过程时，您会明白我的意思。
And this is not just for one slot.
这不仅是针对一个插槽。
It's going to specify an order of slots.
将指定插槽的顺序。
And so our hash function h is going
因此，我们的哈希函数h将继续
to take the universe of keys and also take
拿钥匙的宇宙，也拿
what we're going to call the trial count.
我们将其称为试用计数。
So if you're lucky-- well, you get lucky in your first trial.
因此，如果您很幸运，那么您在第一次审判中会很幸运。
And if you're not, you hope to get lucky in your second trial,
如果不是，您希望在第二次审判中会很幸运，
and so on and so forth.
等等等等。
But the hash function is going to take two arguments.
但是hash函数将接受两个参数。
It's going to take the key as an argument,
它将把键作为参数，
and it's going to take a trial, which is an integer between 0
并且要进行试用，它是0到0之间的整数
to n minus 1, all right?
到n减1，好吗？
And it's going to produce-- just like the chaining hash function
就像链哈希函数一样，它将产生
it's going to produce a number between 0 and m minus 1, right?
它会产生一个介于0和m减1之间的数字，对吗？
Where m is the number of slots in the table.
其中，m是表中的插槽数。
All right.
好吧。
So that's the story.
这就是故事。
In order to ensure that you are using the hash table
为了确保您正在使用哈希表
corresponding to open addressing properly, what you want
对应于正确打开地址，您想要什么
is-- and this is an important property-- that h k 1,
是-这是一个重要的特性-hk 1，
so that's a key that you're given.
所以这是给你的钥匙。
And this could be an arbitrary key, mind you.
请注意，这可以是任意键。
So arbitrary key k.
因此，任意密钥k。
And what you have in terms of the slots that
以及您所拥有的广告位
are being computed is this, h k 1, h k 2,
正在计算的是hk 1，hk 2
and so on and so forth to h k n minus 1.
依此类推，直到hkn减1。
And what you want is for this vector
而你想要的就是这个向量
to be a permutation of 0 1 and so on to n minus 1.
是0 1的排列，依此类推直到n减1。
And the reason for this hopefully is clear.
希望这样做的原因很明确。
It's because you want to be able to use
这是因为您希望能够使用
the entirety of your hash table.
整个哈希表。
You don't want particular slots to go unused.
您不希望使用特定的插槽。
And when you get to the point where the number of elements n
而当您到达元素数量n
is pretty close to m, and maybe there's just one slot left, OK?
非常接近m，也许只剩下一个插槽，好吗？
And you want to fill up this last slot with this key k
您想用此键k填充最后一个插槽
that you want to put in there, and what
你想放在那里，还有什么
you want to be able to say is that for this arbitrary key k
您想说的是，对于这个任意密钥k
that you want to put in there that the one slot that's free--
您想要放在那里的那一个免费插槽-
and it could be that first slot.
可能是第一个插槽。
It could be the 17th slot.
它可能是第17个广告位。
Whatever-- That eventually the sequence of probes
无论如何-最终的探查顺序
is going to be able to allow you to insert into that slot.
将能够允许您插入该插槽。
All right?
好吧？
And we generalize this notion into
我们将这个概念概括为
the uniform hashing assumption in a few minutes,
几分钟后统一哈希假设，
but hopefully this makes sense from a standpoint
但希望从角度来看这是有道理的
of really load balancing the table
真正平衡表的负载
and ensuring that all slots in the table
并确保表格中的所有插槽
are sort of equal opportunity slots.
是机会均等的机会。
That you're going to be able to put keys in them as long as you
只要您能够将钥匙放入其中
probe long enough that you're going to be able to get there.
探测足够长的时间，您将能够到达那里。
Now of course the fact that you're
现在，当然，事实是
using one particular slot for one particular key
为一个特定的键使用一个特定的插槽
depends on the order of keys that you're
取决于您的按键顺序
inserting into this table.
插入此表。
Again, you'll see that as we go through an example, all right?
再次，您将看到我们通过一个示例，对吗？
So that's the set up.
这就是设置。
That's the open addressing notion.
这是开放的寻址概念。
And that as you can see, we're just
如您所见，我们只是
going to go through a sequence of probes
将经历一系列的探究
and our hash function is going to tell us
我们的哈希函数将告诉我们
what the sequences is, and so we don't need any pointers
序列是什么，所以我们不需要任何指针
or anything like that.
或类似的东西。
So let's take a look at how this might work in practice.
因此，让我们看一下这在实践中如何工作。
So maybe the easiest thing to do is to run through an example,
因此，也许最容易做的就是通过一个例子，
and then I'll show you some pseudocode.
然后我将向您展示一些伪代码。
But let's say that I have a table here,
但是，假设我在这里有一张桌子，
and I'm going to concentrate on the insert operation.
我将专注于插入操作。
And I'm going to start inserting things into this table.
我将开始在此表中插入内容。
And right here I have seven slots up there.
在这里，我在那里有七个插槽。
So let's say that I want to insert 586 into the table,
假设我要在表格中插入586，
and I compute h of 586 comma 1, and that gives me 1.
我计算出h为586逗号1，即得出1。
OK?
好？
This is the first insert.
这是第一个插入。
So I'm going to go ahead and stick 586 in here, all right?
所以我继续将586插入此处，好吗？
And then I insert, for argument's sake, 133.
然后，为了论证，我插入133。
I insert 204 out here.
我在这里插入204。
And these are all things because the hash table is empty.
这些都是因为哈希表为空。
481 out here and so on.
481在这里等等。
And because the hash table is empty,
而且由于哈希表为空，
my very first trial is successful, all right?
我的第一次审判成功了，好吗？
So h of 481-- I'm not going to write this all out, but h 481 1
所以481的h-我不会全部写出来，但是h 481 1
happens to be 6 and so on.
碰巧是6，依此类推。
All right?
好吧？
Now I get to the point where I want to insert 496.
现在我要插入496。
And when I try to insert 496, I have h 496 1.
当我尝试插入496时，我有496 1。
It happens to be 4.
碰巧是4。
OK?
好？
So the first thing that happens is I go in here,
所以发生的第一件事就是我进入这里
and I say oops.
我说哦
This slot is occupied, because this-- I'm
这个插槽已被占用，因为-
going to have a special flag associated with an empty slot,
将有一个与空插槽相关的特殊标志，
and we can say it's none.
我们可以说不是。
And if it's not none, then it's occupied.
如果不是全无，那它就会被占用。
And 204 is not equal to none.
204不等于无。
So I look at this, and I say the first probe actually failed.
所以我看了一下，我说第一个探测实际上失败了。
OK?
好？
And so h 496 1 equals 4 fails, so I need to go do h 496 2.
因此，h 496 1等于4失败，所以我需要执行h 496 2。
And h 496 2 may also fail.
并且h 496 2也可能失败。
You might be in a situation where h 496 2 gives you 586.
您可能处于h 496 2给您586的情况。
So this was h 496 1 h 496 2 might give you 586.
因此，这是h 496 1 h 496 2可能会给您586。
And finally it may be that h 496 3, which is your third attempt,
最后可能是h 496 3，这是您的第三次尝试，
equals 3.
等于3。
So you go in, and you say great.
所以你进去，你说的很好。
I can insert 496.
我可以插入496。
And let me write that in bold here.
让我在这里用黑体字写出来。
Out there.
在那里。
All right?
好吧？
So pretty straightforward.
非常简单。
In this case, you've gone through three trials in order
在这种情况下，您已经按顺序进行了三个试验
to find an empty slot.
查找一个空插槽。
And so the big question really here is
所以真正的最大问题是
other than taking care of search and delete, how long is
除了照顾搜索和删除，还有多长时间
this process going to take?
这个过程要走吗？
All right?
好吧？
And I'm talking about that in a few minutes,
我过几分钟再说
but let me explain, now that you've
但让我解释一下，既然您已经
seen insert, how search would work, right?
看到插入，搜索将如何工作，对吗？
Or maybe I get one of you guys to explain to me
或者也许我让你们一个人向我解释
once you have insert, how would search work?
插入后，搜索将如何工作？
Someone?
有人吗
Someone from the back?
有人从后面吗？
No one.
没有人。
You guys are always answering questions.
你们总是在回答问题。
Yeah, all the way in the back.
是的，一直在后面
AUDIENCE: Would you just do the same kind
听众：你会做同样的事情吗
of probing [INAUDIBLE] where you find it or you don't find it?
探测[音频不清晰]在哪里找到还是找不到的？
PROFESSOR: Right.
教授：对。
So you do exactly.
因此，您完全可以。
It's very similar to insert.
插入非常相似。
You have a situation where you're
您遇到的情况是
going to none would indicate an empty slot.
如果全都不做，则表示插槽为空。
And you can think of this as being a flag.
您可以将其视为一个标志。
And in the case of insert, what you did was you--
在插入的情况下，您所做的就是-
insert k v would say keep probing.
插入kv表示继续探测。
I'm not going to write the pseudocode for it.
我不会为它编写伪代码。
Keep probing until an empty slot is found.
继续进行探测，直到找到一个空插槽。
And then when it's found, insert item.
然后找到它，插入项目。
And as long as you have the permutation property
并且只要您具有置换属性
that we have up there, and given that m is greater than
我们在那里，并且考虑到m大于
or equal to n, you're guaranteed that insert
或等于n，则可以确保插入
is going to find a slot.
将要找到一个插槽。
OK?
好？
That's the good news.
那是个好消息。
Now it might take awhile, and so we
现在可能需要一段时间，所以我们
have a talk about performance a bit later, but it'll work.
稍后再讨论性能，但它会起作用。
OK?
好？
Now search is a little bit different.
现在搜索有点不同。
You're searching for a key k, and you essentially
您正在寻找密钥k，并且本质上来说
say you're going to keep probing.
说你要继续探测。
And you say as long as the slots encountered
你说只要遇到槽
are occupied by keys not equal to k.
被不等于k的键占用。
So every time you probe, you go in there
因此，每次探测时，您都会进入
and you say I got a key.
你说我有一把钥匙
I found a hash for it.
我为此找到了一个哈希。
I go to this particular slot.
我去这个特定的位置。
I look inside of it, and I check to see
我看里面，我检查看看
whether the key that's stored inside of it
是否存储在其中的密钥
is the same as the key I'm searching for.
与我要搜索的键相同。
If not, I go to the next trial.
如果没有，我去下一次审判。
If it is, then I return it.
如果是，那么我将其退回。
Right?
对？
So that's pretty much it.
就是这样。
And we keep probing until you either encounter k or find
我们一直在探索，直到您遇到k或找到
an empty slot.
一个空插槽。
And this is the key.
这就是关键。
No pun intended.
无双关语。
A notion which is that when you find an empty slot,
一个想法是，当您发现一个空插槽时，
it means that you have failed to discover this key.
这表示您未能找到此密钥。
You fail to-- yeah, question back there?
您没有-是的，回到那里问吗？
AUDIENCE: What happens if you were to delete a key though?
听众：但是，如果您要删除密钥会怎样？
PROFESSOR: I'll make you answer that question for a cushion.
教授：我让你回答一下这个问题。
So we'll get to delete in a minute.
因此，我们将在一分钟之内删除。
But I want to make sure you're all
但是我想确保你们都
on board with insert and search.
在船上进行插入和搜索。
OK?
好？
So these are actually fairly straightforward in comparison
因此，相比之下，这些实际上非常简单
to delete.
删除。
It's not like delete is much more complicated,
并不是说删除要复杂得多，
but there is a subtlety there.
但那里有一个微妙之处。
And so that's kind of neat, right?
这很整洁吧？
I mean this actually works.
我的意思是这确实有效。
So if you had a situation where you were just accumulating
因此，如果您遇到的情况只是在积累
keys, and you're looking for the number of distinct elements
键，并且您正在寻找不同元素的数量
in the stream of data that was coming in,
在传入的数据流中，
and that was pretty much it with respect to your program,
就您的程序而言，就差不多了
you'd never have to delete keys, and this would be all
您将不必删除密钥，仅此而已
that you'd have to implement.
您必须实施。
Right?
对？
But let's talk about delete.
但是，让我们谈谈删除。
Every once in awhile we'd want to delete a key?
我们偶尔想删除一个密钥吗？
Yeah, you had a question?
是的，您有问题吗？
AUDIENCE: I have a question about search.
听众：我有一个关于搜索的问题。
Why do you stop searching once you find an empty slot?
找到空插槽后为什么停止搜索？
PROFESSOR: Because you're searching.
教授：因为您在搜索。
So what that means is that you're
所以那意味着你是
looking to see if this key were already in the table.
查看该键是否已在表中。
And if key were already in the table,
如果键已经在表中，
you want to return the value associated with that key.
您想要返回与该键关联的值。
If you find an empty slot, since you're
如果您发现一个空位，因为
using the same deterministic sequence of probes
使用相同的确定性探针序列
that you would have if you had inserted it,
如果您将其插入的话，
then-- that make sense?
那么-有意义吗？
Good.
好。
All right.
好吧。
So so far so good?
到目前为止到目前为止还好吗？
That's what works for insert and search.
这就是插入和搜索的原理。
Let's talk delete.
让我们谈谈删除。
So back there.
所以回到那里。
How does delete work?
删除如何工作？
AUDIENCE: Well [INAUDIBLE] if you
观众：好吧[听不清]
search until you find the none and assume
搜索，直到找到一个都没有并假设
that the key you're searching for was not put in there.
您要搜索的密钥没有放在此处。
But let's say you had one that was in that slot before
但是，假设您之前有一个插槽
and it got put back in, but then you
然后放回去，但是然后你
delete the one that was in the slot before.
删除以前在插槽中的那个。
PROFESSOR: Great, great.
教授：太好了。
You haven't told me how to fix it yet,
您还没有告诉我如何解决它，
but do you have the guts for this?
但是你对此有胆量吗？
No.
没有。
OK, I think this veers to the right.
好吧，我认为这是对的。
I always wanted to do this to somebody in the back.
我一直想对后面的人这样做。
All right.
好吧。
Whoa.
哇
All right, good catch.
好的，很好。
All right.
好吧。
OK.
好。
So you pointed out the problem, and I'm
所以你指出了问题，我
going to ask somebody else for a solution.
要问别人一个解决方案。
All right?
好吧？
But here's the problem.
但这就是问题所在。
Here's the problem, and we can look
这是问题所在，我们可以看一下
at it from a standpoint of that example right there.
从那里的那个例子的角度来看。
Let's say for argument's sake that I'm searching-- now
出于争论的原因，我现在正在搜索
I've done all of the inserts that I have up there, OK?
我已经完成了所有在那里的插入，好吗？
So I've inserted 496.
所以我插入了496。
All right?
好吧？
Then I delete 586 from the table, OK?
然后我从表中删除586，好吗？
I delete 586 from the table.
我从表中删除586。
So let's just say that what I end up
所以我们只说我的结局
doing-- I have 586, 133, 496, and then
在做-我有586、133、496，然后
I have 204, and then a 481.
我有204，然后是481。
And this is 0, 1, 2, et cetera.
这是0、1、2等。
So I'm deleting 586, and let's say I replace it with none.
所以我要删除586，假设我将其替换为无。
OK?
好？
Let's just say I replace it with none.
可以说我什么也没有替换。
Now what happens is that when I search for 496, according
现在发生的是，当我搜索496时，
to this search algorithm what am I going to get?
这种搜索算法我将得到什么？
AUDIENCE: None.
听众：没有。
PROFESSOR: Well the first slot I'm going to look at is 1,
教授：我要看的第一个广告位是1
and according to this search algorithm,
然后根据这种搜索算法
I find an empty slot, right?
我发现一个空插槽，对吗？
And when I find an empty slot, I'm
当我发现一个空位时，我
going to say I failed in the search.
会说我搜索失败。
If you encounter k, you succeed and return the key value pair,
如果遇到k，则成功，并返回键值对，
right?
对？
Success means you return the value.
成功意味着您返回价值。
And if you encounter an empty slot,
如果您遇到一个空插槽，
it means that you've decided that this key is not
这意味着您已经确定此密钥不是
in the table.
在桌子上。
And you say couldn't find it, right?
你说找不到，对不对？
That make sense?
有道理？
So this is obviously wrong, right?
所以这显然是错误的，对吧？
Because I just inserted 496 into the table.
因为我刚刚在表中插入了496。
So this would fail incorrectly.
因此，这将错误地失败。
So failed to find the key, which is OK.
所以找不到密钥，没关系。
I mean failure is OK if the key isn't there.
我的意思是，如果钥匙不在那儿，失败就可以了。
But you don't want to fail incorrectly.
但是您不想错误地失败。
Right?
对？
Everyone buy that?
每个人都买吗？
Good.
好。
All right.
好吧。
So how do I fix it.
那么我该如何解决。
Someone else?
其他人？
How do I fix this?
我该如何解决？
Someone who doesn't have a cushion.
没有坐垫的人。
All right, you.
好吧，你。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] you can mark that spot by a, and when
听众：[听不清]您可以用a标记该点，以及何时
search comes across a, you just [INAUDIBLE].
搜索遇到一个，你只是[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Right, great answer.
教授：对，很好的答案。
We're now going to have to do a couple of different things
我们现在将不得不做一些不同的事情
for insert and search, OK?
进行插入和搜索，好吗？
It's going to be subtly different,
情况会有所不同，
but the first thing we're going to do
但是我们要做的第一件事
is we're going to have this flag,
是我们要有这个标志
and I'll just call it delete me flag.
我将其称为“删除我”标志。
OK?
好？
And we're going to say that when I delete something,
我们要说的是，当我删除某些内容时，
replace deleted item with not the non flag,
用非标记替换已删除的项目，
but a different flag that we'll call delete me.
但是我们将其称为“删除我”
Is different from none.
与众不同。
And that's going to be important,
这将很重要，
because now that you have a different flag,
因为现在您有了一个不同的标志，
and you replace 586 with delete me,
然后您将586替换为删除我，
you can now do different things in insert versus search, right?
您现在可以在插入和搜索中执行不同的操作，对吗？
So in particular, what you would do
所以特别是你会怎么做
is you'd have to modify this slightly,
您是否需要对此稍作修改，
because the notion of an empty slot
因为空插槽的概念
means that you're looking for none, right?
表示您什么都不找，对吧？
And all it means is that-- well actually in some sense,
它的全部意思是-实际上在某种意义上，
the pseudo code doesn't really change
伪代码并没有真正改变
because if you say you either encounter k
因为如果你说你遇到k
or you would-- even if you encounter a delete me,
否则，即使您遇到删除我的情况，
you keep going.
你继续前进。
All right?
好吧？
That's the important thing.
那很重要。
So I guess it does change, because I assume
所以我想它确实会改变，因为我假设
that you have only two cases here,
你这里只有两种情况
but what you really have now are three cases.
但是您现在真正拥有的是三种情况。
The three cases are when you're doing
这三种情况是您在做的时候
the search is that you encounter the key, which
搜索是您遇到钥匙，
is the easy case.
很简单。
You return it.
您退还。
You return the value.
您返回值。
Or you can encounter a delete me flag, in which case
否则您可能会遇到“删除我”标志
you keep going.
你继续前进。
OK?
好？
And if you encounter an empty slot, which
如果您遇到一个空插槽，
corresponds to none, at that point you know
对应于无，那时候你知道
you failed and the key doesn't exist in the table.
您失败了，并且表中不存在密钥。
All right?
好吧？
So let me just write that out.
所以让我把它写出来。
Insert treats delete me the same as none.
插入对待删除我就像没有。
But search keeps going and treats it differently.
但是搜索一直在进行，并以不同的方式对待它。
And that's pretty much it.
就是这样。
So what would happen in our example?
那么在我们的例子中会发生什么呢？
Well, going through exactly the same example,
好吧，通过完全相同的示例，
we started from here, and then we decided to delete 586.
我们从这里开始，然后我们决定删除586。
And so if we replaced 586 not with none, but with delete me,
因此，如果我们不将586替换为无，而是删除我，
and the next time around when you search for 496,
下次您搜索496时，
you're searching for 496.
您正在搜索496。
And what would happen is that you
然后会发生的是你
would go look at 586-- the slot that contained 586,
会去看586-包含586的插槽
and you see that there's a delete me flag in there.
并且您看到那里有一个Delete me标志。
And so you go to the next trial.
因此，您可以进行下一次审判。
And then in the next trial, you discover that, in this case,
然后在下一个试验中，您发现在这种情况下，
you have-- I'm sorry.
你有-对不起。
I had 204 first as the first trial,
我第一次测试有204个
and then in the second trial I had 586.
然后在第二次审判中我有586。
And I would continue beyond the second trial
我将继续进行第二次审判
and get to third trial, and in fact return 496 in this case.
并进行第三次审判，实际上在这种情况下返回了496。
I would get to returning 496 in my third trial, which
我将在第三次审判中返回496，这是
is exactly what I want.
正是我想要的
The interesting thing here is that you can reuse storage.
有趣的是，您可以重用存储。
I mean the whole point of deleting
我的意思是删除的重点
is that you can take the storage and insert other keys in there.
就是您可以拿起存储并在其中插入其他密钥。
Once you've freed up the storage.
释放存储空间后。
And you can do that by making insert treat delete me
你可以通过使插入对待删除我来做到这一点
the same as the none.
和没有一样。
So the next time you want to insert you
所以下次您要插入
could-- if you happen to index into the index corresponding
可能-如果您碰巧索引到对应的索引中
to 586, you can override that.
到586，您可以覆盖它。
The delete me flag goes away, and some other key--
Delete me标志消失，其他一些键-
call it 999 or something-- would get in there.
称为999之类的东西-就会进入那里。
And you're all set with that.
所有人都为此设定。
OK?
好？
Any questions?
任何问题？
This all makes sense?
这一切有意义吗？
So you could imagine coding this up with an array structure
因此，您可以想象使用数组结构对此进行编码
is fairly straightforward.
非常简单。
What remains here to be discussed
这里还有什么要讨论
is how well does this work, right?
效果如何？对吗？
You have this extra requirement on the hash function
您对散列函数有此额外要求
corresponding to creating an extra argument
对应于创建一个额外的参数
as an input to it, which is this trial count.
作为输入，这就是该试用计数。
And you'd like to have this nice property of corresponding
而且您想拥有对应的这个不错的属性
to a permutation.
排列。
Can we actually design hash functions like this?
我们真的可以设计这样的哈希函数吗？
And we'll take a look at a bad hash function,
我们来看一个错误的哈希函数，
and then at a better one.
然后再做一个更好的。
So let's talk about probing strategies, which
因此，让我们谈谈探测策略，
is essentially the same as taking a hash function
本质上与采用哈希函数相同
and changing it so it is actually
并更改它，以便实际上
applicable to open addressing.
适用于开放式寻址。
So the notion of linear probing is
因此，线性探测的概念是
that you do h k i equals h prime k, which
你做hki等于h素数k，
is some hash function that you've chosen,
是您选择的一些哈希函数，
plus i mod m, where this is an ordinary hash function.
加上i mod m，这是一个普通的哈希函数。
OK?
好？
So that looks pretty straightforward.
因此，这看起来非常简单。
What happens here?
这里会发生什么？
Does this satisfy the permutation argument?
这是否满足置换参数？
Before I forget.
在我忘记之前。
Does it satisfy the permutation property
它是否满足置换属性
that I want h k 1, h k 2, h k m minus 1 to be a permutation?
我想让hk 1，hk 2，hk m减1是一个排列？
That make sense?
有道理？
Yep, yep.
是的，是的
Because I then I start adding.
因为然后我开始添加。
The mod is precisely kind of this round robin cycle,
Mod正是这种循环循环的一种，
so it's going to satisfy the permutation.
因此它将满足排列要求。
That's good.
那很好。
What's wrong with this?
这怎么了
Someone?
有人吗
AUDIENCE: The fact that [INAUDIBLE] keys, which they're
听众：[音频不清晰]键是
all filled, then if you hit anywhere in here [INAUDIBLE]
全部填满，那么如果您在此处的任何地方点击[听不清]
list of consecutive keys.
连续键的列表。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
That's excellent.
太好了
Excellent, excellent answer.
很好，很好的答案。
So this notion of clustering is basically
所以这个聚类的概念基本上是
what's wrong with this probing strategy.
这种探测策略有什么问题。
And in fact, I'm not going to do this particular analysis,
实际上，我将不进行此特定分析，
but I'll give you a sense of why the statement I'm going to make
但我会告诉您为什么我要发表的声明
is true.
是真的。
But the notion of clustering is that you
但是集群的概念是
start getting consecutive groups of occupied slots, OK?
开始获得连续的占用插槽组，好吗？
Which keep growing.
哪些保持增长。
And so these clusters get longer and longer.
因此，这些集群变得越来越长。
And if you have a big cluster, it's
如果您有一个大型集群，那就是
more likely to grow bigger, right?
变得更大的可能性更大吧？
Which is bad.
不好
This is exactly the wrong thing for load balancing, right?
这对于负载均衡而言确实是错误的，对吗？
And clustering is the reverse of load balancing, right?
集群是负载平衡的逆向，对吗？
If you have a bunch of clumps and you
如果你有一堆团块，你
have a bunch of empty space in your table, that's bad.
桌子上有一堆空的空间，这很糟糕。
Right?
对？
The problem with linear probing is
线性探测的问题是
that once you start getting a cluster, given the, let's say,
假设您开始建立集群后，
the randomness in the hash function, and h prime k
哈希函数的随机性，以及h素数k
is a pretty good hash function and can randomly go anywhere.
是一个非常不错的哈希函数，可以随机访问任何地方。
Well, if you have 100 slots and you have a cluster of size 4,
好吧，如果您有100个插槽，并且集群大小为4，
well there's a for 4/100 chance, which is obviously
好，有4/100的机会，这很明显
four times greater than 1/100, even I can do that,
是1/100的四倍，即使我可以做到，
to go into those four slots.
进入这四个插槽。
And if you going into those four slots
如果您进入这四个位置
you're going to keep going down to the bottom,
您将继续走到底
and you're going to make that a cluster of size five, right?
然后将要组成一个大小为5的簇，对吗？
So that's the problem the linear probing,
这就是线性探测的问题，
and you can essentially argue through making
而且您基本上可以通过
some probabilistic assumptions that if, in fact, you
一些概率假设，实际上，如果您
use linear probing that you lose your average constant time
使用线性探测会浪费平均时间
look up in your hash table for most load factors.
在哈希表中查找大多数负载因子。
So what's happening out here pictorially really
所以这真的发生在图片上
is that you have a table and let's say you have a cluster.
是您有一张桌子，假设您有一个集群。
And this is your cluster.
这就是您的集群。
So if your h k 1-- it doesn't really
因此，如果您的港币1 –不是
matter what it is-- but h k i maps to this cluster,
不管它是什么-但是h ki映射到该群集，
then you're going to-- linear probing
那么您将要-线性探测
says that the next thing you're going to try
说你要尝试的下一件事
is if you map to 42 in the cluster,
如果您在集群中映射到42，
the next thing you're going to try
接下来你要尝试的
is 43, 44, until you get maybe to this slot here, which is 57,
是43、44，直到您可能到达此处的这个插槽，即57，
for argument's sake.
为了论证。
Right?
对？
So you're going to keep going, and you're
所以你要继续前进，而你
going to try 15 times in this relatively dumb fashion
将以这种相对愚蠢的方式尝试15次
to go down to get to the open slot, which is 57.
下到空位，即57。
And oh, by the way, at the end of this you
哦，顺便说一句
just increased your cluster length by one.
只是将群集长度增加了一个。
All right?
好吧？
So it doesn't really work.
因此，它实际上不起作用。
And in fact, under reasonable probabilistic assumptions
实际上，在合理的概率假设下
in terms of what your hash functions are,
就您的哈希函数而言，
you can say that when you have alpha, which is essentially
你可以说当你有阿尔法时
your load factor, which is n over m less than 0.99,
您的负载系数，即m小于0.99的n倍，
you see clusters of size log n, OK?
您看到大小为log n的簇，好吗？
Right.
对。
So this is a probabilistic argument,
所以这是一个概率论证，
and you're assuming that you have a hash function that's
并且假设您有一个哈希函数
a pretty good hash function.
一个相当不错的哈希函数。
So h prime k can be this perfect hash function, all right?
那么h素数k可以是这个完美的哈希函数，好吗？
So there's a problem here beyond the choice of h
所以这里的问题超出了h的选择
prime k, which is this hash function that worked really
素数k，这是真正起作用的哈希函数
well for chaining.
适合链接。
All right?
好吧？
And the problem here is the linear probing aspect of it.
这里的问题是它的线性探测方面。
So what does that mean?
那是什么意思呢？
If you have clusters of theta log n,
如果您有theta log n的簇，
then your search and your insert are not
那么您的搜索和插入都不是
going to be constant time anymore.
将不再是恒定的时间。
Right?
对？
Which is bad in a probabilistic sense.
从概率的角度来看，这是不好的。
OK?
好？
So how do we fix that?
那么我们该如何解决呢？
Well, one strategy that works reasonably well
好吧，一种有效的策略
is called double hashing.
称为双重哈希。
And it literally means what it says.
它的字面意思就是它所说的。
You have to run a couple of hashes.
您必须运行几个哈希。
And so the notion of double hashing is that you have h k i
因此，双重哈希的概念是
equals h1 k plus i h2 k mod m.
等于h1 k加i h2 k mod m。
And h1 and h2 are just ordinary hash functions.
h1和h2只是普通的哈希函数。
OK?
好？
Now the first thing that we need to do
现在我们要做的第一件事
is figure out how we can guarantee a permutation, right?
弄清楚我们如何保证排列，对吗？
Because we still have that requirement,
因为我们仍然有这个要求，
and it was OK for the linear probing part,
线性探测部分还可以，
but you still have this requirement
但您仍然有此要求
that you need a permutation.
您需要排列。
And so those of you who are into number theory,
所以你们那些从事数论的人，
can you tell me what property, what neat property of h2 and m
你能告诉我h2和m的什么性质
can we ask for to guarantee a permutation?
我们可以要求保证排列吗？
Do you have a question?
你有问题吗？
You already do.
你已经做过了
Do you have a question?
你有问题吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: [INAUDIBLE] relatively prime.
教授：[听不清]相对素数。
OK, good.
好好
So I figured some of you knew the answer,
所以我想你们当中有些人知道答案，
but I've seen you before.
但我以前见过你
Right.
对。
Exactly right.
非常正确。
Relatively prime.
相对素数。
Just hand it to Victor.
只需将它交给维克多。
So h2 k and m being relatively prime,
所以h2 k和m是相对素数的
if that implies a permutation.
如果这意味着排列。
It's similar to what we had before.
它与我们以前的相似。
You're multiplying this by i. i keeps increasing,
你乘以我。我一直在增加，
and you're going to roll around.
然后你会滚来滚去。
All right?
好吧？
I mean you could do a proof of it,
我的意思是你可以证明这一点，
but I'm not going to bother.
但我不会打扰。
The important thing here is that you can now
重要的是您现在可以
do something as simple as m equals 2 raised to r,
做简单的事情，例如m等于2升到r，
and h2 k for all k is odd, and now you're in great shape.
h2 k对于所有k都是奇数，现在您的状态很好。
You can have your array to be 2 raised
您可以将阵列提高2
to something, which is what you really want.
某种东西，这是您真正想要的。
And you just use h2 k.
而您只使用h2 k。
You could even take a regular hash function
您甚至可以使用常规的哈希函数
and truncate it to make sure it's odd.
并截断它以确保它是奇数。
You can do a bunch of things.
您可以做很多事情。
There's hash functions that produce odd values,
散列函数会产生奇数值，
and you can use that.
您可以使用它。
All right?
好吧？
And so double hashing works fairly well in practice.
因此，双哈希在实践中效果很好。
It's a good way of getting open addressing to work.
这是一种开放式地址工作的好方法。
And in order to prove that open addressing actually
并且为了证明开放地址实际上
works to the level at which chaining works,
在链接工作的水平上工作，
we have to make an assumption corresponding
我们必须做出一个对应的假设
to uniform hashing.
统一哈希。
And I'm not going to actually do a proof,
而且我实际上不会做证明，
but it'll be in the notes.
但会在笔记中。
But I do want to talk about the theorem and the result
但是我确实想谈一谈定理和结果
that the theorem implies, assuming
定理所隐含的
you have the uniform hashing assumption.
您有统一的哈希假设。
And let me first say that this is not
首先让我说这不是
the same as simple uniform happening, which
就像发生简单的制服一样
talks about the independence of keys in terms of their mapping
讨论键映射的独立性
to slots.
到插槽。
The uniform hashing assumption says
统一哈希假设说
that each key is equally likely to have
每个键都具有相同的可能性
any one of the m factorial permutations--
m个阶乘置换中的任何一个-
so we're talking about random permutations
所以我们在谈论随机排列
here-- as its probe sequence.
此处-作为其探测序列。
All right?
好吧？
This is very hard to get in practice.
这很难付诸实践。
You can get pretty close using double hashing.
您可以使用双散列获得相当接近的效果。
But nobody's discovered a perfect hash function,
但是没有人发现完美的哈希函数，
deterministic hash function that satisfies this property.
满足此属性的确定性哈希函数。
At least not that I know off.
至少不是我知道。
So what does this imply?
那么，这意味着什么呢？
Assuming that you have this and double hatching
假设您有这个并且有双重阴影
gives you this property, to a large extent what this means is
赋予您此属性，这在很大程度上意味着
that if alpha is n over m, you can
如果alpha在m上是n，则可以
show that the cost of operations such as search, insert, delete,
表明诸如搜索，插入，删除，
et cetera.
等等。
And in particular we talk about insert
特别是我们谈论插入
is less than or equal to 1 divided by 1 minus alpha.
小于或等于1除以1减去alpha。
OK?
好？
So obviously this goes as alpha tends to 1.
因此很明显，随着alpha趋向于1。
As alpha tends to 1, the load factor in the table gets large,
随着alpha趋于1，表中的负载因子变大，
and the number of expected probes
以及预期的探测数量
that you need to do when you get an insert grows.
插入插入后需要执行的操作会增加。
And if alpha is 0.99, you're going, on average,
如果alpha为0.99，则平均而言，
require 100 probes.
需要100个探针。
It's a constant number, but it's a pretty bad constant.
这是一个常数，但它是一个非常糟糕的常数。
Right?
对？
So you really want alpha to be fairly small.
因此，您确实希望alpha很小。
And in practice it turns out that you
实际上，您发现
have to re-size you're open addressing table
必须重新调整您要打开的地址表的大小
when alpha gets beyond about 0.5, 0.6 or so,
当alpha超过约0.5、0.6左右时，
because by then you're really in trouble.
因为那时你真的很麻烦。
Remember this is an average case we're talking about.
请记住，这是我们正在谈论的平均情况。
All of this is using a probabilistic assumption.
所有这些都是使用概率假设。
But as you get to high alphas, suddenly
但是当您达到高Alpha值时，突然
by the time you get to 0.7, open addressing
到0.7时，打开寻址
doesn't work well in relation to an equivalent table
相对于等效表而言效果不佳
with the overall number of slots that
与插槽总数
correspond to a changing table, OK?
对应一张换尿布台好不好
So open addressing is easy to implement.
因此，开放寻址很容易实现。
It uses less memory because you don't need pointers.
它使用较少的内存，因为您不需要指针。
But you better be careful that your alpha stays around 0.5
但是您最好注意您的alpha值保持在0.5左右
and no more.
仅此而已。
So all that means is you can still use it.
因此，这意味着您仍然可以使用它。
You just have to re-size your table.
您只需要调整桌子的大小即可。
You have slightly different strategies
您的策略略有不同
for resizing your table when you use open
在使用open时调整表的大小
addressing as opposed to chaining hash tables.
寻址而不是链接哈希表。
All right?
好吧？
So that's a summary of open addressing.
这就是开放地址的摘要。
I want to spend some time on cryptographic hashes
我想花一些时间在加密散列上
in the time that I have left.
在我离开的时候
I guess I have a few minutes left.
我想我还剩几分钟。
But any questions about open addressing?
但是对开放式寻址有任何疑问吗？
Yep?
是的
AUDIENCE: On this delete part, what's
听众：在这个删除部分，什么是
going to happen if, say, you fill the table up and then
例如，如果您填满桌子，然后发生
delete everything, and then you start searching.
删除所有内容，然后开始搜索。
Isn't that going to be bad because it's
那不是很糟糕，因为
going to search through everything?
要搜索所有内容？
PROFESSOR: So that's right.
教授：没错。
The bad thing about open addressing
开放式寻址的坏处
is that delete isn't instantaneous, right?
是删除不是瞬时的，对吗？
In the sense that if you deleted something from the link list
从某种意义上说，如果您从链接列表中删除了某些内容
in your chaining table, then even
在您的链接表中，然后甚至
if you went to that same thing, the chain got smaller,
如果你去做同样的事情，连锁店会变小，
and that helps you, because your table now has lower load.
这对您有所帮助，因为您的表现在具有较低的负载。
But there's a delay associated with load
但是与负载有关的延迟
when you have the delete me flag.
当您有Delete me标志时。
OK?
好？
So in some sense the alpha that you want to think about,
因此，从某种意义上讲，您要考虑的Alpha，
you should be careful as to how you define alpha.
您应该谨慎定义Alpha。
And that's one of the reasons why
这就是为什么
when you get alpha being 0.5, 0.6
当您得到的alpha为0.5、0.6
you get into trouble, because if you have all these delete
您会遇到麻烦，因为如果您将所有这些删除
me flags, they're still hurting you.
我的旗帜，他们仍然在伤害你。
AUDIENCE: And when you resize do those
观众：当您调整大小时，
delete me flags get deleted?
删除我的标志会被删除吗？
PROFESSOR: When you completely resize
教授：完全调整大小后
and you redo the whole thing, then you
然后重做整个事情，然后
can clean up the delete me's and turn them into nones
可以清理删除我的东西并将它们变成无
because you're rehashing it.
因为您正在重新哈希它。
All right.
好吧。
So yeah, back there.
是的，回到那里。
Question?
题？
AUDIENCE: Yes, can you explain how you got the equation
听众：是的，您能解释一下如何得出方程式吗？
that the cost of operation insert is less than
插入的操作成本小于
or equal to 1 over [INAUDIBLE].
或等于[听不清]的1。
PROFESSOR: That's a longish proof,
教授：这是一个长期的证明，
but let me explain to you how that comes out.
但让我向您解释结果如何。
Basically the intuition behind the proof
基本上是证明背后的直觉
is that we're going to assume some probability p.
我们将假设某个概率p。
And initially you're going to say something
首先，您要说些什么
like if the table, your p-- I'll just write this out here--
就像桌子一样，您的p--我会在这里写出来-
is m minus n divided by m.
是m减去n除以m。
So what is that?
那是什么
Right now I have n elements in the table,
现在我在表中有n个元素，
and I have m slots, OK?
我有m个插槽，好吗？
So the probability that my very first trial is going to succeed
所以我的第一次审判会成功的可能性
is going to be m minus n divided by m, because these
将是m减去n除以m，因为这些
are the number of empty slots.
是空插槽的数量。
And assuming my permutation argument,
并假设我的排列参数
I could go into one of them.
我可以进入其中之一。
And so that's what I have here.
这就是我在这里所拥有的。
And if you look at what this is, this is 1 minus alpha, OK?
如果您看这是什么，这是1减去alpha，好吗？
And so then you run off and you remember
所以你逃跑了，你记得
6041 or the high school probability course
6041或高中概率课程
that you take, and you say generally speaking,
您所接受的，通常来说，
you're going to be no worse than p for every trial.
每次试用都不会比p差。
And so if you assume the worst and say
因此，如果您假设最坏的情况并说
every trial has a probability of success of p,
每个审判都有成功的概率p，
the expected number of trials is 1/p, OK?
预期的试验次数是1 / p，好吗？
And that's how you got the 1 over 1 minus alpha.
这就是您获得1比1减去alpha的方式。
So you'll see that written in gory detail in the notes.
因此，您会在注释中看到详细内容。
All right?
好吧？
OK.
好。
Expected to have a little more time
预计会有更多时间
in terms of talking about cryptographic hashes,
在谈论加密哈希时，
but cryptographic hashes are not going to be on the quiz.
但是加密哈希将不再是测验。
This is purely material FYI.
仅供参考。
For your interest only.
仅出于您的兴趣。
And again I have some notes on it,
再说一遍，
but I want to give you a sense of the other kinds of hashes
但我想让您了解其他类型的哈希
that exist in the world, I guess.
我猜这是存在的。
And hashes that are used for many different applications.
以及用于许多不同应用程序的哈希。
So maybe the best way of motivating this
所以也许是激发这一点的最好方法
is through an example.
通过一个例子。
So let's talk about an example that
所以我们来谈一个例子
is near and dear to every security person's heart
在每个安全人员的心中都是亲爱的
and probably to people who aren't interested in security
可能对那些对安全性不感兴趣的人
as well, which is password storage.
以及密码存储。
So think about how, let's say, Unix systems
因此，考虑一下Unix系统如何
work when you type in your password.
当您输入密码时可以正常工作。
You're typing in your password [INAUDIBLE],
您正在输入密码[音频不清晰]，
and this is true for other systems as well,
其他系统也是如此
but you have a password.
但是您有密码。
And my password is a permutation of my first daughters
我的密码是我第一个女儿的排列
first name.
名字。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
Yeah, but haven't given it away, right?
是的，但是还没有放弃，对吧？
Haven't given it away.
还没有放弃。
And so this password is something
所以这个密码就是
that I'm typing in every day, right?
我每天都在输入，对吗？
Now the sum check that needs to happen
现在需要进行总和检查
to ensure that I'm typing in the right password.
确保输入正确的密码。
So what is a dumb way of doing things.
那么什么是愚蠢的做事方式。
What's a dumb way of building systems?
什么是愚蠢的构建系统方式？
AUDIENCE: Storing [INAUDIBLE].
听众：存储[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: This is kind of a freebie.
教授：这是一种免费赠品。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: In situ hashing.
教授：原位哈希。
That's better.
这样更好
So you'd store it.
所以你要存储它。
I offered the dumb way.
我提供了愚蠢的方式。
So there's a perfectly valid answer.
因此，有一个完全正确的答案。
So you could clearly store this in plain text in some file
因此，您可以清楚地将其以纯文本格式存储在某个文件中
and you could call it slash etc slaw password.
您可以将其称为斜线等色拉密码。
And you could make it read for the work, right?
您可以将其读为工作，对吗？
And that'd be great, and people do that, right?
那会很棒，人们会这样做，对吗？
But what you would rather do is you
但是你宁愿做的是你
want to make sure that even the sysadmin doesn't know
想要确保即使系统管理员也不知道
my password or your password, right?
我的密码或您的密码，对不对？
So how do you do that?
那你怎么做呢？
Well you do that using a cryptographic hash that
好吧，您可以使用加密哈希来实现
has this interesting property that is one way, OK?
有这个有趣的属性是一种方法，好吗？
And what that means is that given h of x-- OK,
这意味着给定x的h-好吧，
this is the value of the hash-- it
这是哈希值-
is very hard to find the x such that x basically
很难找到这样的x
hashes to this value.
哈希值。
So if h of x equals let's call it q,
因此，如果x的h等于q，
then you're only given h of x.
那么您只得到x的h。
And so what do you do now?
那你现在怎么办？
Well, it's beautiful.
好吧，很漂亮。
Assuming you have this one way hash, this cryptographic hash,
假设您有这种单向哈希，这种密码哈希，
in your etc slash password file, you
在您的等斜杠密码文件中，您
have something like login name, [INAUDIBLE],
具有类似登录名，[音频不清晰]，
which happens to be the hash of my daughter's first name,
碰巧是我女儿名字的哈希，
or something.
或者其他的东西。
But this is what's stored in there and the same thing
但这是存储在其中的东西
for a bunch of different users, right?
对很多不同的用户吧？
So when I log in and I type in the actual password,
因此，当我登录并输入实际密码时，
what does the system do?
该系统做什么？
What does the system do?
It hashes it.
它哈希它。
It takes x prime, which is the typed in password, which
它需要x个质数，这是输入的密码，
may or may not be equal to my password,
可能等于或可能不等于我的密码，
because somebody else might be trying to break in,
因为可能有人试图闯入，
or I just mistyped, or forgot my daughter's first name,
或者我只是输错了字，或者忘记了我女儿的名字，
which would be bad.
那就不好了
And it will just check to see-- it doesn't need x, because it's
它只会检查-不需要x，因为它是
stored h of x in the system, so it doesn't need x.
将x的h存储在系统中，因此不需要x。
So if we just compare against what I typed in,
因此，如果我们将其与我输入的内容进行比较，
it would compute the hash again.
它将再次计算哈希。
And then would let me in assuming that these things
然后让我假设这些事情
matched and would not let me in if it didn't.
匹配，如果不匹配，不会让我进入。
So now we can talk about-- and I don't have time for this,
所以现在我们可以谈论-我没有时间
but you can certainly read up on it on Wikipedia
但您当然可以在Wikipedia上阅读它
and a bunch in the notes.
和一堆笔记。
You can talk about what properties
你可以说说什么属性
should this hash function have, namely one way collision
该散列函数应具有的功能，即单向冲突
resistance, in order to solve these problems
抵抗，以解决这些问题
and other problems.
和其他问题。
I'm happy to stick around and answer questions.
我很乐意坚持并回答问题。